

CONTACT



+33 767036103



pierre.lague@protonmail.com



jakcrimson.github.io



84 rue Ste Catherine, Lille

SOFT SKILLS

- Team work
- Critical thinking
- Creativity
- Adaptability
- · Problem solving
- Curiosity

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Pytorch, Tensorflow, Keras
- DL, NLP, MARL
- SQL, MySQL
- Data Mining
- AWS
- Git

PROGRAMMING LANGUAGE

- Python / R
- Scala
- Java
- C++/C/C#

SPOKEN LANGUAGE

- English (bilingual, 945 TOEIC)
- French (native)

PIERRE LAGUE

STUDENT IN MACHINE LEARNING

APPLYING FOR A PHD POSITION

PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

I am a machine learning student pursuing a Master of Science degree with hands-on experience in developing, implementing, and optimizing AI projects. Through a blend of theoretical knowledge and practical work in public laboratories and corporate settings, I've honed my skills as a quick learner, critical thinker, and problem solver. My track also includes multiple trips abroad making me an open-minded person with a high sense of adaptability.

WORK EXPERIENCE

ML Engineer (apprenticeship) - Sudo Group

September 2024

Joined the R&D team at Sudo Group in Lille, FR. ML Engineer for cloud optimization and various research topics ranging from forecasting to NLP.

Al Research Engineer Intern - CNRS

January 2023 - February 2023

Effectively led a performance evaluation of a newly developed ML algorithm for 3D point cloud classification.

Al Research Engineer Intern - CNRS

May 2022 - August 2022

Led a cutting-edge project on semantic segmentation for aerial drone imagery funded by the National Research Institute.

Student Tutor in Mathematics, CS and English

Sept 2021 - May 2022

Al Engineer Intern - Accenture Technology, Nantes

April 2021 - July 2021

EDUCATION

Sept. 2023 MSc. - University of Lille

Master in Machine Learning - graduated 1st year

Sept. 2022 - June 2024 MSc. - UTC

Master in Complex Systems Engineering - 1st year with honors GPA 4.0/5

Sept. 2021 - June 2023 BSc. - University of Bretagne Sud

Bachelor in Computer Science - graduated, class major GPA 4.5/5

2019 - 2021 - IT Associate Degree - University of South Britany

2016 - Edinburgh Public School

Schooled for 6 months at the English speaking public school Best Student award

2011-2012 - Christchurch Ilam School, New Zealand

Schooled for a year at the English speaking public school